Contact

4379828881 (Mobile) akrsharma86@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/akrsharma7766 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Blueyonder Bastian autostore Autostore

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Punjabi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals AZ-303 Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies

Leadership Development Program

Anil Kumar Sharma

Software Development Manager II @ Best Buy Canada Canada

Summary

Engineering leader with experience in designing and developing customer centric new solutions and maintaining high level of operational excellence for existing softwares.

Lead and learned from team members across globe. Experienced in working with different technologies - Java, Microservices, Cloud (Azure, AWS and Hybrid), APIs, Micro-frontends (Piral), Kubernetes, Docker, GitOps (ArgoCD & Fleet) in both Agile and Waterfall environments. Trying to learn more on Security and machine learning.

Experience

Best Buy Canada Software Development Manager II October 2022 - Present (2 years 7 months) Toronto, Ontario, Canada

As a development leader in supply chain and logistics, I am leading a team of developers and operations engineers to drive warehouse modernization at Best Buy Canada.

- Led the team in the successful go-live of the WMS modernization (BlueYonder) project, ensuring seamless integration and enhanced operational efficiency.
- Played a pivotal role in vendor selection, finalizing initial designs, and meticulously planning and executing the go-live phase.
- Currently implementing Autostore automation to boost operational efficiency in our warehouse and e-commerce fulfillment processes.
- Oversee the daily activities of the development team, ensuring alignment with project goals and timelines.
- Develop and implement software development strategies that align with business objectives and drive innovation.

- Ensure the delivery of high-quality software solutions through rigorous testing and code reviews.
- Work closely with cross-functional teams and stakeholders to gather requirements, provide updates, and ensure successful project outcomes.
- Mentor and support team members in their professional growth and development.

GoSecure

Software Development Manager March 2022 - August 2022 (6 months)

Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Inbox Detection and Response –Development of new age email security solution which enable post-delivery analysis of emails. Managing overall development activities and delivery of new Solution and supporting existing operations.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Defining engineering HLD and vision of new age IDR solution. This includes creation and socializing Architecture diagram, Flow and sequence diagrams
- Review and validate the Low-level designs by team and its alignment to HLD and product vision.
- API definition and swagger documentation. Developed SpringBoot API with connection to multiple Databases i.e. MS SQL and Postgres
- Developing Fleet GitOps deployment pipelines for Spring boot APIs and Services to Kubernetes based Rancher Cluster.
- Setting up Authentication and Authorization for APIs using KeyCloak. Realm,
 Client and Roles creation.
- Micro frontend (pilet) integration to Piral Shell and Feed service.
- Defining Milestones for Project and creation of features/tasks in backlog.
- Played Scrum master role and participated in Sprint planning, Scrum meetings and defining milestones for Project.
- Ensure that team follows the change management processes for releases.
 Introduced semantic versioning to streamlined release management across different components.
- Prepared clear integration points with different teams and lead discussion to align before development. Identified reusable components or existing lesson learnt.
- Exploring new technologies and scoping POCs for development.
- Worked on incident and problem tickets created by customers and resolved performance issue (Solved multiple O(n*2) issues in legacy code)

 Helped customer success along with customer service, DevOps and sales engineers.

Amadeus

6 years 10 months

Software Development Manager April 2018 - February 2022 (3 years 11 months) Bangalore

Overall responsibility of development, operating and supporting Software deployment services for health check and validation used as part of CI/CD &operational activities. These services/products are used for change/recovery validation steps for both legacy and cloud-native applications and help in improving system stability.

Responsibilities

- Defining and delivering validation services that interact with Openshift/
 VM boxes to collect data based on defined operational criteria and provide analysis/results of validations.
- Creating product evolution vision to provide functionality as API and UI based to enable both SRE teams and automation through CI/CD pipeline
- Working with product owners and developers for the delivery of all committed projects on time, on-scope, and adherence to corporate standards and quality.
- Work with Product owners to understanding different user requirements and creating a product roadmap.
- · Resource and budget management for the team.
- Work with developers to review new technologies for taking technology decisions.
- Defining team objectives and translating them into individual objectives for each team member in line with organizational goals.

Member Of Technical Staff

May 2015 - March 2018 (2 years 11 months)

Responsible for automating deployments, which is part of continuous deployment of CICD.

Responsibilities

- Lead development team ensuring quality of solution delivered.
- Working with SRE teams to understand their automation requirement for deployment
- Implementing and Enhancement of tools as per user request.
- Identifying new areas of automation for system stability.

Analysis and low level design for new implementation.

Cognizant Technology Solutions
Associate - Projects
March 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 3 months)
Bengaluru Area, India

Project

Web portal for Medicaid program financed and run jointly by the federal and state governments for low-income people of all ages who do not have the money or insurance to pay for health care. The goal of the program is to provide medical and other health care services to eligible individuals so that they are able to remain as self-sufficient as possible. Medicaid is a state-administered program.

Responsibilities

- Interacting with application users and business analysts to understand technical and functional requirements, determine timelines and provide highlevel design document.
- Acknowledging, investigating issues related to a software application, tracking
- Implementing new Business rules and functionalities.
- Handling heap dump issues.
- · Issue Tracking and timely resolutions.
- Smoke Testing script implementation and automation

UST Global

Software Engineer September 2010 - March 2013 (2 years 7 months) Cochin Area, India

Project

Care management programs apply systems to improve medical practice and assist consumers and their support system to become engaged in a collaborative process designed to manage medical/social/mental health conditions more effectively. The goal of care management is to achieve an optimal level of wellness and improve coordination of care while providing cost-effective, non-duplicative services.

Responsibilities

- Requirement gathering, analysis and technical design for project enhancements.
- Coding and unit testing for application enhancements.

- · Code and Documentation reviews.
- Server Environment issue resolutions.
- Second tier production support for applications.
- Estimation preparations for new Projects.

WE Excel Software Pvt. Ltd.
Software Engineer
December 2008 - August 2010 (1 year 9 months)
Chandigarh Area, India

Project

A new web application i.e. (www.hafedwarehousing.com) was introduced to automate the warehousing process of HAFED (Haryana State Cooperative Supply and Marketing Federation Limited). The project scope was to create a web application and implement it in different Warehouses across Haryana, which consist of training warehouse owners and users.

Responsibilities

- Coding and unit testing for application enhancements.
- Project implementation at client site.
- User training
- Loading initial data to system DB and rectifying the incorrect data.

Education

Punjab Technical University
Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2004 - 2008)

Kendriya Vidyalaya